<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 21:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coding in March</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-19-coding-im-dojo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-19-coding-im-dojo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Despite the beautiful weather, we spent this Saturday morning indoors. This time we got straight into our projects without any introductions. New game elements were added to almost finished games. Games that had just been thought up were started again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/coding_im_dojo_workinprogress.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to implement certain game mechanics, Scratch is the perfect foundation, just like designers who focus on character development or future authors who want to tell their story in a playful way. The biggest project - a Discord chat bot - runs in Python.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programming for Space - Astro Pi Workshop - Part Two</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-29-astropi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-29-astropi/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Brighten up the daily routine of the astronauts on the International Space Station.&amp;rdquo; - Cheer up the everyday life of astronauts on the International Space Station (ISS). That is the goal of the Mission Zero project, which we worked on together on January 29.
&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/astro_pi_mission_zero_key_visual.png" alt="" title="Image (above): ESA">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A total of six children and young people took part. It was about the ISS. It was about temperature, humidity and pressure measurements using appropriate sensors. It was about Python programming on Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s. And on top of that: The workshop took place in cooperation with a South African CoderDojo! Before the programming started, we were able to introduce ourselves to each other in a video call. Partners were found straight away who will send their project together to the astronauts on the ISS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programming for Space - Astro Pi Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-03-programmieren-f%C3%BCr-den-weltraum-astro-pi-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 19:24:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-03-programmieren-f%C3%BCr-den-weltraum-astro-pi-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>Space, infinite expanses. The year is 2021, and these are the adventures of young developers
who write programs together to support the work of the crew of the International Space Station ISS.
This is Astro Pi Mission Zero!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim of the workshop was to develop a program to measure the current humidity on board the ISS
and then communicating this to the astronauts in a personalized message. For this purpose
Astro Pi is used on the ISS for this purpose: a small computer with various sensors to measure the current
temperature, humidity and air pressure as well as an LED matrix consisting of eight by eight LEDs that can be individually controlled.
LEDs that can be controlled individually. However, in order to be able to test the program locally, we used an emulator
emulator that simulates the functionality of the Astro Pi on a website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Astro Pi - Code in Space</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/python-astropi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/python-astropi/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Astro Pi - Code in Space&amp;rdquo; as part of the
project &lt;a href="https://astro-pi.org/mission-zero/">&amp;ldquo;Mission Zero&amp;rdquo; of the RaspberryPi Foundation&lt;/a>, participants will be given the opportunity to write a Python programme,
to write a Python programme that will then be played on the ISS. Participants can create an animation lasting a maximum of 30 seconds,
in which at least the humidity on the ISS is displayed. In addition, participants can greet the astronauts, display the air pressure and temperature
or add pictures. The &amp;ldquo;Online Sense HAT Emulator&amp;rdquo; is used - a programme that simulates the AstroPi computer with sensors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello Bot, how are you?</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/chatbot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/chatbot/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Hello Bot, how are you?&amp;rdquo; participants will gain insight into how to program chatbots.
Chatbots are programs capable of conversing with a user. Participants can choose to use either Scratch or Python.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depending on the participants&amp;rsquo; progress, when using Scratch, they can also utilize the &amp;ldquo;Text-to-Speech&amp;rdquo; extension and create their own blocks (also known as &amp;ldquo;functions&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;subroutines&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning objectives:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Participants understand what a chatbot is.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participants can make the computer say something.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participants can query and use user input.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participants can use conditions to respond to user input.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Participants will need:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>