<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 19:08:24 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Team</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/team/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Us</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/about/</guid><description>The CoderDojo Schöneweide is a club for children and teenagers between 7 and 17 years old who are interested in and enjoy creatively using computers, shaping the digital world, and solving tricky problems. The CoderDojo Schöneweide offers free, project-based workshops.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/contact/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Donations</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/donate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/donate/</guid><description>Would you like to support the work of CoderDojo Schöneweide? Donate to CoderDojo Deutschland e.V. with the purpose &amp;ldquo;Spende Schöneweide&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/events/</guid><description>Events take place twice a month, on Saturdays from 11:00 am to 1:00 pm at the HTW in Schöneweide (Wilhelminenhofstr. 75A, 12459 Berlin). Typically, there is one workshop and a &amp;ldquo;Coding in the Dojo&amp;rdquo; session. No prior knowledge is required!
Workshops | Gain insight into a specific topic from the digital world.
Coding in the Dojo | Bring your project and get help from our mentors, or start a new project.</description></item><item><title>Parents - Newsletter</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/newsletter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/newsletter/</guid><description>Are you a parent and want to stay updated on the latest workshop offerings from CoderDojo Schöneweide? Then sign up for the email newsletter! There, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive all the information about our upcoming workshops for the next month one to two times per month.
To subscribe to the newsletter, simply send a casual email to schoeneweide.berlin@coderdojo.com or click the following button:
Subscribe to Newsletter</description></item><item><title>The digital world is everywhere - Creatively integrating computers into every subject. Our offer for schools and teachers.</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/schools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/schools/</guid><description>The digital world is everywhere. We want children and teenagers in this digital world not only to consume but also to be able to shape it.
Do you want to support your students in learning to shape the digital world?
Feel free to take advantage of our offerings for schools and teachers.
Workshops für teachers Do you have a class set of robots collecting dust in the closet because no one knows how to use them?</description></item><item><title>SDG</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/sdg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/sdg/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Find me from Ottikar</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/finde_mich/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 19:08:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/finde_mich/</guid><description>Developed by one of our ninjas.</description></item><item><title>Fifa in Better</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/fifa_in_besser/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/fifa_in_besser/</guid><description>The football game Fifa is not good enough? Then here is a good alternative from Jujamm.</description></item><item><title>Project of the Karlshorst School</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/karlshorster_schule/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:08:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/karlshorster_schule/</guid><description>This short story was created in cooperation with Karlshorster Schule.</description></item><item><title>Scratch inspiration for coding in the dojo</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/inspiration_coding_im_dojo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:08:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/inspiration_coding_im_dojo/</guid><description>This was a little inspiration for our Ninjas to show particle effects in Scratch.</description></item><item><title>3D-Art with Blender</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/blender/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/blender/</guid><description>In the workshop &amp;ldquo;3D Art with Blender,&amp;rdquo; participants will learn to use the tool Blender to create 3D models. The workshop can be extended by 2 hours to additionally teach participants how to animate models.
Learning objectives:
Participants can navigate the Blender environment. Participants can create simple 3D shapes with Blender. Participants can colorize 3D models. Participants can animate 3D model Participants will need:
A computer with Blender installed.</description></item><item><title>Animating a music video</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-musikvideo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-musikvideo/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Animating a music video&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to make simple animations with Scratch. The animations are created by moving and changing the costumes of characters in Scratch. Depending on the progress of the participants, additional elements such as stage sets can be added.
Learning objectives:
Participants can control the movement of characters in Scratch. Participants understand the difference between characters and costumes. Participants can control the costumes of a character programmatically in Scratch.</description></item><item><title>Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/kuenstliche-intelligenz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/kuenstliche-intelligenz/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Artificial Intelligence&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants explore how AI works and what this technology can be used for. Using the Monkey Game as an example, participants discover how AI &amp;ldquo;learns.&amp;rdquo; Then, with the help of the website Machine Learning for Kids they can train and experiment with AI themselves. The model can also be used in Scratch at the end.
Learning objectives:
Participants know what AI is. Participants know how AI can be trained.</description></item><item><title>Astro Pi - Code in Space</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/python-astropi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/python-astropi/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Astro Pi - Code in Space&amp;rdquo; as part of the project &amp;ldquo;Mission Zero&amp;rdquo; of the RaspberryPi Foundation, participants will be given the opportunity to write a Python programme, to write a Python programme that will then be played on the ISS. Participants can create an animation lasting a maximum of 30 seconds, in which at least the humidity on the ISS is displayed. In addition, participants can greet the astronauts, display the air pressure and temperature or add pictures.</description></item><item><title>Between Ladybugs and Building Blocks</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/karol-und-kara/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/karol-und-kara/</guid><description>In the workshop &amp;ldquo;Between Ladybugs and Building Blocks,&amp;rdquo; participants, with the help of our ladybug Kara and our building block figure Robot Karol, get a first glimpse into the world of programming and algorithms. Kara and Robot Karol are programming environments designed for children and teenagers. First, all participants familiarize themselves with Kara and Karol and can discover functions and possibilities on their own. Then, tasks with various levels of difficulty can be solved or participants can implement their own ideas, such as guiding Karol through a self-built maze.</description></item><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Club / Association</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/verein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/verein/</guid><description>The CoderDojo Schöneweide is a registered association. The non-profit status is pending. We are also a member Dojo of CoderDojo Deutschland e.V..
Membership Anyone can become a member. Simply send us an informal membership application via email. Resignation from membership is also informal and can be done via email.
Documents Satzung Annual reports 2023 2022</description></item><item><title>Creative Programming with Godot</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/godot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/godot/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Creative Programming with Godot&amp;rdquo; is aimed at teenagers or educators and mentors. Here, participants can, after an introduction to game design and an overview of the game engine &amp;ldquo;Godot,&amp;rdquo; design their own &amp;ldquo;platformer&amp;rdquo; game and begin implementation. Educators can explore the challenges and opportunities of game development.
Learning objectives:
Participants have a basic understanding of the game development process. Participants know how to work with Godot fundamentally. Participants can use basic scenes and node trees from Godot.</description></item><item><title>Dashbot Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/dashbot-challenges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/dashbot-challenges/</guid><description>In the Challenges workshop with Dash robots, participants will go through various task setups and learn to control and program a small robot in a playful manner.
As the tasks are very open-ended, participants can develop and try out their own solution ideas.
The DashBots A DashBot can be controlled via a connected iPad using the &amp;ldquo;Wonder&amp;rdquo; app. In the Wonder app, the DashBot can be manually controlled (Control), small programming tasks can be played (Robot Saga), and it can be freely programmed (Developer mode).</description></item><item><title>Datenschutzerklärung</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/datenschutz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/datenschutz/</guid><description>In dieser Datenschutzerklärung (Stand: 26.07.2023) erläutern wir basierend auf der Datenschutz-Grundverordnung (EU) 2016/679 und anwendbaren nationalen Gesetzen, welche personenbezogenen Daten (kurz Daten) wir als Verantwortliche – und die von uns beauftragten Auftragsverarbeiter:innen (z. B. Provider) – verarbeiten, zukünftig verarbeiten werden und welche rechtmäßigen Möglichkeiten Sie haben.
Rechtsgrundlagen Die Datenschutz-Grundverordnung (EU) 2016/679 und das deutsche Bundesdatenschutzgesetz (BDSG). legen den Rahmen fest, in dem wir personenbezogene Daten verarbeiten.
Wir verarbeiten Ihre Daten nur, wenn mindestens eine der folgenden Bedingungen zutrifft:</description></item><item><title>Dramas with llamas</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-theaterstueck/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-theaterstueck/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Dramas with llamas&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to make simple animations with Scratch. The focus of the workshop is on characters speaking and interacting with each other - just like in a theatre play. To ensure that what is said does not overlap, the interaction must be planned in terms of timing: who says what for how long, and so who waits how long? More advanced participants learn how to synchronise the interaction of the characters more efficiently, how to use Scratch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;send&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;receive&amp;rdquo; commands.</description></item><item><title>Hello Bot, how are you?</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/chatbot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/chatbot/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Hello Bot, how are you?&amp;rdquo; participants will gain insight into how to program chatbots. Chatbots are programs capable of conversing with a user. Participants can choose to use either Scratch or Python.
Depending on the participants&amp;rsquo; progress, when using Scratch, they can also utilize the &amp;ldquo;Text-to-Speech&amp;rdquo; extension and create their own blocks (also known as &amp;ldquo;functions&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;subroutines&amp;rdquo;).
Learning objectives:
Participants understand what a chatbot is. Participants can make the computer say something.</description></item><item><title>How to: Look after the child in the workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/parents/dosanddonts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/parents/dosanddonts/</guid><description>Sometimes you try to explain something to your child, but it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t click? With us, it&amp;rsquo;s all about having fun. That&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s important for you as a parent to support your child optimally.
Consider:
your child&amp;rsquo;s individual learning style, including factors like concentration and their own problem-solving methods. your child wants to pursue their own project, not yours! feel free to assist with problems through targeted questions. sometimes, just showing that parents make mistakes too is enough.</description></item><item><title>Improving the world as a software developer</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the world as a software developer&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an initial insight into working as a software developer. In the first part, the participants deal with topics that are close to their hearts, such as climate protection or equal rights, and think together about how software influences society. In the next step, the participants design a piece of software that draws attention to a social issue or that addresses a social problem.</description></item><item><title>Improving the World Through Games</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the World Through Games,&amp;rdquo; participants will get a first glimpse into the work of a game designer. In the first part, participants will discuss whether and how games can positively influence society. Then, participants will design their own game idea and have the opportunity to implement part of the idea using Scratch.
Learning objectives:
Participants will gain an impression of what a game designer does. Participants will be familiar with the fundamental elements of a game concept: story, graphics, sound, micro and macro goals, controls.</description></item><item><title>It speaks!</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-lippensynchronisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-lippensynchronisation/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;It speaks!&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants will gain an insight into how to make fluid animations consisting of individual images with Scratch. In this type of animation, several images are played one after the other, so that a kind of &amp;ldquo;film&amp;rdquo; is created in the mind - like a flip book, but digital! Lip synchronisation is a special type of frame-by-frame animation: a digital figure moves its mouth A digital figure moves the mouth so that the movements match the words spoken.</description></item><item><title>Legal Notice</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/impressum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/impressum/</guid><description>Information according to § 5 TMG. JavaScript must be enabled to display contact details.
Contact person: Linda Fernsel Address: Show Address
Email: Show Email
Phone number: Show Phone Number
Some icons on our site are based on the corresponding solid icons from Font Awesome and are licensed under CC-BY-4.0.</description></item><item><title>Making digital greeting cards</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Making digital greeting cards&amp;rdquo;, participants will gain an insight into how to make animations with Scratch and create beautiful digital greeting cards. The animations are created through the movement, costume changes and graphic effects of characters in Scratch. Depending on the progress of the participants, other means of animation can also be used, such as cloning figures or using the &amp;ldquo;colouring pen&amp;rdquo;.
Learning objectives:
Participants can play sounds in Scratch Participants can create simple graphics using the Scratch graphics editor.</description></item><item><title>mBot Obstacle Course</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/mbot-labyrinth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/mbot-labyrinth/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;mBot Obstacle Course,&amp;rdquo; participants navigate an mBot through an obstacle course. After a programming phase, two teams compete against each other: Who can be the first to burst the balloon in the middle of the course? Line and proximity sensors are used for traversing the course.
The mBlock programs for controlling the mBots are shared by the participants with on-site mentors, who then execute the programs. Since the mBots are captured by a camera mounted on the ceiling, participants can follow live to see if their program is working.</description></item><item><title>Pet App</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/octostudio-haustierapp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/octostudio-haustierapp/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Pet App&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants get an insight into how to program a digital pet that gets hungry and needs to be fed. OctoStudio is used for this purpose, which is an app for mobile devices that allows you to program apps. After a short round of inspiration, participants, together with their mentors, parents, or alone, use the guide provided by us to program a basic pet app and get to know OctoStudio.</description></item><item><title>Photo filter app</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/pocketcode-gesichtserkennung/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/pocketcode-gesichtserkennung/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Photo filter app&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to programme intelligent photo filters, so-called &amp;ldquo;lenses&amp;rdquo;, such as those found on Instagram or SnapChat. PocketCode, an app for mobile devices that can be used to programme apps, is used for this. After a short, creative warm-up exercise in which the participants design four filters on different topics in a short space of time, together with their mentor, parents or alone, the participants use the instructions we have put together to create their own photo filter.</description></item><item><title>Processing</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/processing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/processing/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Processing&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants learn about the Processing tool, which can be used to generate images and animations. can be generated. To do this, participants take their first steps in programming with Java and solve their first puzzles before inventing their own creative images.
Learning objectives:
Participants can operate the Processing environment Participants know basic processing commands Participants need:
Computer with Java 11, JRE11 and the Processing IDE installed</description></item><item><title>Shared Story</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/gemeinsame-geschichte/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/gemeinsame-geschichte/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Shared Story&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants first learn what programming is. With the game &amp;ldquo;Living Robot,&amp;rdquo; they get to know the basics of algorithmic thinking. Then, they can take their first steps in programming with Scratch and get to know the programming environment.
Separately from the workshop (e.g., in German and art classes), participants choose a story (e.g., a myth they have studied). This story is divided into small sections and distributed among participant groups.</description></item><item><title>Storyboarding and animations with Scratch</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-animationen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-animationen/</guid><description>In this workshop, participants design animations on topics that concern them in everyday life, such as friendship and the environment. Participants will gain an insight into elements of an animated film and how it is created: Brainstorming, storyboarding, animation and testing.
Learning objectives:
Participants can identify emotion-transporting elements of an animated film concept. Participants can create a storyboard for a scene. Participants can create simple graphics using the Scratch graphics editor.</description></item><item><title>What is the CoderDojo? - For parents</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/parents/infos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/parents/infos/</guid><description>What is the aim of CoderDojo Schöneweide? CoderDojo Schöneweide is an organisation that aims to teach children and young people about programming in a fun way. You can find a short teaser video here.
Can my child take part? Yes.
However, it would be helpful if they can already read. We also have an upper age limit of 17 years (17 years is ok, 18 is not). After that, you are welcome to join as a mentor :)</description></item></channel></rss>