<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 19:08:24 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Team</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/team/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Us</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/about/</guid><description>The CoderDojo Schöneweide is a club for children and teenagers between 7 and 17 years old who are interested in and enjoy creatively using computers, shaping the digital world, and solving tricky problems. The CoderDojo Schöneweide offers free, project-based workshops.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/contact/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Donations</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/donate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/donate/</guid><description>Would you like to support the work of CoderDojo Schöneweide? Donate to CoderDojo Deutschland e.V. with the purpose &amp;ldquo;Spende Schöneweide&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/events/</guid><description>Events take place twice a month, on Saturdays from 11:00 am to 1:00 pm at the HTW in Schöneweide (Wilhelminenhofstr. 75A, 12459 Berlin). Typically, there is one workshop and a &amp;ldquo;Coding in the Dojo&amp;rdquo; session. No prior knowledge is required!
Workshops | Gain insight into a specific topic from the digital world.
Coding in the Dojo | Bring your project and get help from our mentors, or start a new project.</description></item><item><title>Parents - Newsletter</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/newsletter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/newsletter/</guid><description>Are you a parent and want to stay updated on the latest workshop offerings from CoderDojo Schöneweide? Then sign up for the email newsletter! There, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive all the information about our upcoming workshops for the next month one to two times per month.
To subscribe to the newsletter, simply send a casual email to schoeneweide.berlin@coderdojo.com or click the following button:
Subscribe to Newsletter</description></item><item><title>The digital world is everywhere - Creatively integrating computers into every subject. Our offer for schools and teachers.</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/schools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/schools/</guid><description>The digital world is everywhere. We want children and teenagers in this digital world not only to consume but also to be able to shape it.
Do you want to support your students in learning to shape the digital world?
Feel free to take advantage of our offerings for schools and teachers.
Workshops für teachers Do you have a class set of robots collecting dust in the closet because no one knows how to use them?</description></item><item><title>SDG</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/sdg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/home/sdg/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Find me from Ottikar</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/finde_mich/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 19:08:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/finde_mich/</guid><description>Developed by one of our ninjas.</description></item><item><title>Fifa in Better</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/fifa_in_besser/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/fifa_in_besser/</guid><description>The football game Fifa is not good enough? Then here is a good alternative from Jujamm.</description></item><item><title>Interdisciplinary experience at the HTW</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-06-28-interdisziplin%C3%A4re-erfahrung-an-der-htw/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:53:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-06-28-interdisziplin%C3%A4re-erfahrung-an-der-htw/</guid><description>*This experience report about the work in CoderDojo was written by a former member in March 2022 (editor&amp;rsquo;s note).
In the third semester of the Master&amp;rsquo;s degree course in Business Communication, I was able to encounter the development of the project and soon-to-be association CoderDojo Schöneweide at HTW Berlin. At the information event, I particularly liked the motivation and vision of confronting children of a young age with the world of programming in a playful way.</description></item><item><title>Myth Workshop at Karlshorst Elementary School</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-06-16-sagen-workshop-an-der-grundschule-karlshorst/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-06-16-sagen-workshop-an-der-grundschule-karlshorst/</guid><description>On 17.05.2023 and 24.05.2023 we were at the Karlshorst elementary school and organized a Scratch workshop on the topic of sagas together with the 6th grade students.
On May 17th, after a short introduction, we started directly with the robot game. The pupils were faced with the difficult task of programming our robot Ilja so that he could satisfy his hunger for toast with peanut butter. This required many intermediate steps, such as unwrapping the toast and inserting the knife into the peanut butter.</description></item><item><title>Project of the Karlshorst School</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/karlshorster_schule/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:08:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/karlshorster_schule/</guid><description>This short story was created in cooperation with Karlshorster Schule.</description></item><item><title>Scratch inspiration for coding in the dojo</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/inspiration_coding_im_dojo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:08:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/dojo-projects/inspiration_coding_im_dojo/</guid><description>This was a little inspiration for our Ninjas to show particle effects in Scratch.</description></item><item><title>Processing Workshop: Programming Pictures and Animations</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-03-10-processing-workshop-bilder-und-animationen-programmieren/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 11:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-03-10-processing-workshop-bilder-und-animationen-programmieren/</guid><description>On March 4, we held the Processing-Worksop. We looked at the program “Processing” with children aged 12 and over - for many it was their first time programming with text. How exciting! And really well mastered.
The aim of the workshop was to provide a fun introduction to programming by using Processing to create images and animations. Participants were given a brief introduction to the color theory of the RGB system as used by computer screens.</description></item><item><title>FEZ - The Pixel Worlds February 23</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-02-18-die-pixelwelten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 17:10:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-02-18-die-pixelwelten/</guid><description>On two weekends, February 11 and 12 and February 18 and 19, kids were able to make their own VR goggles, design PixelArt or play Jump&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;Run SuperMario live in the gym at the FEZ leisure and recreation center.
We took part in the CoderDojo on the 11th and 12th with two workshops each entitled “Robot competitions”. We didn&amp;rsquo;t really have anything to do with competitions. Instead, similar to the crazy lab in November, there were a wide variety of challenges that had to be mastered with DashBots.</description></item><item><title>Experiences from a semester at CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-02-15-die-erfahrungen-aus-einem-semester-beim-coderdojo-sch%C3%B6neweide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 15:56:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-02-15-die-erfahrungen-aus-einem-semester-beim-coderdojo-sch%C3%B6neweide/</guid><description>In the following lines, I would like to share my impressions of CoderDojo Schöneweide, which I received during the winter semester 22/23. I myself am a student at the HTW and came to the CoderDojo via the selection list of the HTW&amp;rsquo;s AWE modules.
My first impressions were of some really friendly people who are enthusiastic and enjoy what they do. As well as working on the well thought out workshops, there is a lot going on behind the scenes here.</description></item><item><title>New CMS!</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-01-25-neues-cms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 17:01:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-01-25-neues-cms/</guid><description>As part of our AWE at the HTW, we (Philipp and Jonas) have been working on making our website a little better. You&amp;rsquo;re probably thinking that something visible to you readers has changed. But when developing websites, a lot happens in the background that you don&amp;rsquo;t usually see directly. Our project was about simplifying the creation of these blog posts. Before our project, the creation of blog articles was much more complicated and very technical.</description></item><item><title>Figma Prototyping Workshop: Adventskalender-App</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-12-17-figma-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 16:27:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-12-17-figma-workshop/</guid><description>Kurz vor Weihnachten fand ein Figma Prototyping Workshop für Kinder im Alter von 6 bis 12 Jahren statt. Bei diesem Workshop ging es darum, einen individuellen Adventskalender mit der Design-Software Figma zu erstellen. Die Teilnehmenden wurden mit einem vorgegebenen Adventskalender-Template ausgestattet, das sie nach ihren eigenen kreativen Vorstellungen gestalten sollten.
Adventskalender-Template in Figma
Die 5 Teilnehmenden haben sich bei der Gestaltung des Adventskalenders viele verschiedene Möglichkeiten ausgedacht. Einige haben hinter den Türchen Bilder hochgeladen, andere haben eigene kleine Designs erstellt.</description></item><item><title>December-Workshop: Animations with Scratch</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-27-dezember-workshop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-27-dezember-workshop/</guid><description>On November 26, the workshop “It speaks!” took place, in which participants practiced animating with Scratch. They were able to speak a word, e.g. the name of their favorite desert, play it back with Scratch and then animate the lip movements of a stick figure to match.
With the help of our Lip Sync toolkit, the participants were quickly able to enjoy their first successes.
After we had previously held this workshop online, this was the first time it could take place in person.</description></item><item><title>FEZ Crazy Lab Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-09-fez-verruecktes-labor-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 17:27:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-09-fez-verruecktes-labor-workshop/</guid><description>Last weekend, our Dashbot workshop took place for the second time at the FEZ, a popular event for kids and parents alike. Dashbot? - They&amp;rsquo;re those cute little blue robots that you can do all sorts of crazy things with. As part of the crazy lab at the FEZ, interested children were able to let off steam. The highlight is that the robots can be programmed in a beginner-friendly way. This means that all actions can also be carried out automatically.</description></item><item><title>Löt Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-10-08-loet-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 16:54:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-10-08-loet-workshop/</guid><description>Programming is already pretty cool, but in the cold temperatures our fingers freeze on the keyboards and we look for new challenges. For example, soldering. This was made possible by contacts at xHain and we are happy about this collaboration, even if we had to leave our cozy room in Schöneweide for it.
You probably already know how our programming workshops work from the other blog articles. If not, then you should definitely read them!</description></item><item><title>Our code of conduct</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-09-21-verhaltenskodex/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 17:15:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-09-21-verhaltenskodex/</guid><description>We have recently given some thought to how we want to organize our cooperation in the team of the CoderDojo team as well as in workshops and other events we organize. The result of this have been recorded in our new Code of Conduct!
Our Code of Conduct consists of three parts: General principles of conduct, conduct towards team colleagues and Behavior towards children and young people. The general part defines rules that we would like to see in our dealings with each other.</description></item><item><title>Badges in CoderDojo</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-09-19-abzeichen-im-coderdojo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-09-19-abzeichen-im-coderdojo/</guid><description>Today you can find badges or trophy systems in many learning platforms or learning apps. They are designed to motivate learning enthusiasts such as children, for example, in order to promote fun and learning progress. I asked myself to what extent badges and trophy systems can encourage children to learn programming and how they influence a child&amp;rsquo;s fun and self-motivation.
To do this, I first looked at research on the use of badges in education.</description></item><item><title>Coding in March</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-19-coding-im-dojo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-19-coding-im-dojo/</guid><description>Despite the beautiful weather, we spent this Saturday morning indoors. This time we got straight into our projects without any introductions. New game elements were added to almost finished games. Games that had just been thought up were started again.
If you want to implement certain game mechanics, Scratch is the perfect foundation, just like designers who focus on character development or future authors who want to tell their story in a playful way.</description></item><item><title>Hack Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-12-htw-hackt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-12-htw-hackt/</guid><description>In movies, hackers often sit in dark rooms, shrouded in eternal night. Our workshop in cooperation with HTW Hackt showed that there is another way: it was a sunny Saturday afternoon, blue skies and bright rooms in which our ninjas could train. The topic this time was XSS, which stands for cross-site scripting and simply put means executing code on websites via input fields.
Since you can&amp;rsquo;t just hack in everywhere, the people from HTW Hackt created a website themselves, which the participants were allowed to explore.</description></item><item><title>Programming for Space - Astro Pi Workshop - Part Two</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-29-astropi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-29-astropi/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Brighten up the daily routine of the astronauts on the International Space Station.&amp;rdquo; - Cheer up the everyday life of astronauts on the International Space Station (ISS). That is the goal of the Mission Zero project, which we worked on together on January 29. A total of six children and young people took part. It was about the ISS. It was about temperature, humidity and pressure measurements using appropriate sensors. It was about Python programming on Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>CoderDojo Schöneweide - Corporate Design</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-31-corporate-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-31-corporate-design/</guid><description>I came across the “CoderDojo Schöneweide” project at HTW and wanted to take part in it. As my strengths lie more in the area of design and programming, I looked for an alternative job to mentoring within the Dojo. I was welcomed with open arms and found out with the help of the other members that the team was still looking for someone to take care of the corporate design and revise the current design.</description></item><item><title>Neues Format: Coding im Dojo</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-15-coding-im-dojo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-15-coding-im-dojo/</guid><description>To get the new year off to a good start, the first Coding im Dojo of the year took place on January 15. As with every Coding im Dojo, the focus is on making and creativity. All participants can come to us with their own topics and the mentors will endeavor to support your projects in word and deed and help you develop and tinker 🧑‍🏫.
The children were able to take part in this “Coding in the Dojo” either on site or online via BigBlue-Button.</description></item><item><title>Minecraft Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-08-minecraft/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-08-minecraft/</guid><description>We, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary workshop at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus on January 8th, 2022. The motto this time was &amp;ldquo;MINECRAFT&amp;rdquo;! Or rather Minecraft Redstone. Redstone is an object that serves as a manufacturing recipe. This makes it possible to build lines made of so-called redstone dust. These lines can then transmit redstone signals. This also enables the construction of larger redstone circuits. We showed our young participants how it is possible to build small circuits in Minecraft.</description></item><item><title>Chatbot with Scratch 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-12-11-chatbot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-12-11-chatbot/</guid><description>Last week, we met again on the Wilhelminenhof campus of HTW Berlin and let the children program a chatbot with the help of Scratch. Once all the children had found their way to us, we got started after a short round of introductions and the question “What is your favorite robot (Bender Futurama!)”.
The children got to grips well with the week&amp;rsquo;s topic. The first attempts to design a chatbot were accomplished with the support of mentors.</description></item><item><title>Women in computer science</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-10-frauen-in-der-informatik/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-10-frauen-in-der-informatik/</guid><description>Computer science has its origins in the 19th century. The founder of this science and the first female programmer was Ada Lovelace with her algorithm for calculating Bernoulli numbers with the Analytical Engine calculating machine. From the beginning of the computer until the 1980s, programming was considered a “typical female profession”. The first electronic computer was used in 1942 for war purposes on behalf of the US Army. Especially during the Second World War, only women did programming, which is now hard to believe, as the computer science industry today only has a very small proportion of women.</description></item><item><title>Between beetles and building blocks workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-24-zwischen-kaefern-und-blaukloetzen-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-24-zwischen-kaefern-und-blaukloetzen-workshop/</guid><description>We, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary workshop on 20.11.21 at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus.
Under the motto “Between Beetles and Building Blocks”, our little ladybird Kara and our brick figure Robot Karol helped us to understand the world of programming and algorithms. Kara and Robot Karol are programming environments designed for children and young people.
After a brief introduction to Kara, the children were able to get to know and operate the program independently.</description></item><item><title>Gruselige Party zum 10. Geburtstag von CoderDojo</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-01-grusel-geburtstagsparty-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-01-grusel-geburtstagsparty-workshop/</guid><description>Can you believe it? CoderDojo is already celebrating its tenth anniversary! And we, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, have turned 2 years old. These milestones need to be celebrated! Just in time for Halloween, we, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary spooky birthday party workshop at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus. Wilhelminenhof campus.
There were delicious homemade cupcakes, balloons, costumes and, of course, young, determined programmers! Everything a CoderDojo party needs to be a success.</description></item><item><title>FEZ Phenomena Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-25-fez-phaenomenien-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 22:24:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-25-fez-phaenomenien-workshop/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the fall vacations in Berlin and the FEZ Berlin invited children and their families to marvel, explore and play. play. The fall vacations were not supposed to be boring. We from CoderDojo Schöneweide were also there with 2 voluntary organized workshops on site. Our energetic mentors played and programmed together with the children small, lively Dash robots that could be operated with a tablet.
There were a total of 5 different challenges to overcome at both workshops.</description></item><item><title>Improving the world through games</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-11-mit-spielen-die-welt-verbessern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-11-mit-spielen-die-welt-verbessern/</guid><description>We from CoderDojo Schöneweide also offered a volunteer workshop at the Treptow-Köpenick Volunteer Days as part of the Berlin Volunteer Days. On Saturday morning, 11.09.21, everything revolved around how we can improve the world with games. There are two questions we need to answer. Firstly, what does it actually mean to make the world a better place? Secondly, how can we do this with games? To approach these questions naturally, we first discussed our favorite games.</description></item><item><title>Your own lens</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-20-deine-eigene-lense/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-20-deine-eigene-lense/</guid><description>On Friday, 20.08.2021, three mentors held a workshop on the topic of “Your own Lense”. Four children and their parents took part in the workshop.
The idea for our workshop was for the children to program their own photo filters with the “Pocket Code” app and have fun doing so. At the beginning, we did a short round of introductions to warm up. Then we played a game in which we mentors set a topic for each round.</description></item><item><title>Our first presence dojo during the Corona pandemic - A how-to</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-erster-live-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-erster-live-workshop/</guid><description>Two weeks before our July workshop, the idea came up that it might be possible to hold it live and outdoors. Enthusiastic about the idea, we first had to find out which framework conditions applied. In the end, the organizational effort was surprisingly easy to manage in 2 weeks:
The location
In the shadow of the rising numbers at the end of July, “outside but still with access to electricity” was a relevant key point.</description></item><item><title>Summer, sun, games! An experience report</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-juli-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-juli-workshop/</guid><description>In the middle of the summer vacations, the sun only peeked through the clouds from time to time on Thursday, but there was no end of fun programming games.
Programmieren unter freiem Himmel - ein erster Eindruck Under the open sky in a relaxed picnic atmosphere, all participants were finally able to talk to each other in person. It was a bit unusual for everyone to get to know each other first, but eventually everyone had their say (including the parents!</description></item><item><title>June Workshop 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-06-juni-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-06-juni-workshop/</guid><description>On 22.06.2021 we got together and organized a scratch workshop. It was quite a small workshop this time, so close to the summer vacations, but the small group made the atmosphere very relaxed.
As always at the beginning of a workshop, the mentors introduced themselves so that the participants knew who they could turn to if they had any questions. This time, it was also possible for the participants to introduce themselves right at the beginning.</description></item><item><title>Scratch Week 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-20-scratch-week/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-20-scratch-week/</guid><description>Just in time for Scratch Week, we held a workshop on 20.05.2021 in which where children could realize their own projects with the help of Scratch. 8 pupils of different ages took part and 4 mentors who organized and led the workshop. The theme of the workshop was “Magical Arcade”. A theme that the children could use as a guide and that gave them plenty of scope for ideas.
At the beginning of the workshop, the mentors introduced themselves so that the participants knew who to ask if anything was unclear.</description></item><item><title>Programming for Space - Astro Pi Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-03-programmieren-f%C3%BCr-den-weltraum-astro-pi-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 19:24:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-03-programmieren-f%C3%BCr-den-weltraum-astro-pi-workshop/</guid><description>Space, infinite expanses. The year is 2021, and these are the adventures of young developers who write programs together to support the work of the crew of the International Space Station ISS. This is Astro Pi Mission Zero!
The aim of the workshop was to develop a program to measure the current humidity on board the ISS and then communicating this to the astronauts in a personalized message. For this purpose Astro Pi is used on the ISS for this purpose: a small computer with various sensors to measure the current temperature, humidity and air pressure as well as an LED matrix consisting of eight by eight LEDs that can be individually controlled.</description></item><item><title>Girls Day 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-04-22-girls-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-04-22-girls-day/</guid><description>At our Girls Day 2021 workshop, we primarily explored the interplay between software and society. On April 22, 2021, 18 schoolgirls sat down together with 7 mentors (virtually, of course) and explored the question of how explored the question of how software influences our social lives. Does it do that at all? Where does it do it? And is it even good the way it does it?
The participants showed particular interest in the topics of environmental protection and sustainability.</description></item><item><title>“Photo filters with PocketCode - A workshop with kein Abseits e.V.”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-03-16-workshop-pocketcode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-03-16-workshop-pocketcode/</guid><description>You can use fun filters and “lenses” on SnapChat and Instagram, that add additional elements to your photo - for example, a pair of whiskers in just the right place. In our first PocketCode workshop, we designed and programmed our own smart photo filters.
We ran the workshop together with mentors from kein Abseits e.V., so that they can pass on their knowledge to their mentees. Only a few mentees at kein Abseits e.</description></item><item><title>“Make your own games - Our first online workshop”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-09-08-workshop-game-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 13:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-09-08-workshop-game-design/</guid><description>Designing a game is quite complicated: You have to think about the story you want to tell, what graphics or music you need, you have to design user-friendly menus and controls and of course you also have to manage to motivate the users! Of course, you can&amp;rsquo;t learn all this in a single workshop, but at least we were able to offer the participants of our online workshop on September 5, 2020 an introduction.</description></item><item><title>“Introduction to computer science for primary school pupils - you can learn a lot even without a computer!”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-04-03-workshop-einstieg-in-die-informatik/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 13:51:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-04-03-workshop-einstieg-in-die-informatik/</guid><description>How do I tell a robot how to make a sandwich, clear garbage in the park or catch a balloon? On March 5, 2020, a sixth grade class from the Grundschule an der Wuhlheide was able to find out at our introductory programming workshop at HTW. programming at the HTW. One of the most important findings from this workshop was certainly Computer science education is possible with analog games even without expensive technical equipment!</description></item><item><title>“Welcome to CoderDojo Schöneweide”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2019-10-27-willkommen-beim-coderdojo-osw/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 19:59:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2019-10-27-willkommen-beim-coderdojo-osw/</guid><description>Welcome to CoderDojo Schöneweide! Here in our blog you can follow our current projects and keep up to date with our events.
We are a group of students from the HTW Berlin who have made it their goal to organize a programming workshop for children and young people between the ages of 7 and 17 at the university.</description></item><item><title>3D-Art with Blender</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/blender/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/blender/</guid><description>In the workshop &amp;ldquo;3D Art with Blender,&amp;rdquo; participants will learn to use the tool Blender to create 3D models. The workshop can be extended by 2 hours to additionally teach participants how to animate models.
Learning objectives:
Participants can navigate the Blender environment. Participants can create simple 3D shapes with Blender. Participants can colorize 3D models. Participants can animate 3D model Participants will need:
A computer with Blender installed.</description></item><item><title>Animating a music video</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-musikvideo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-musikvideo/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Animating a music video&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to make simple animations with Scratch. The animations are created by moving and changing the costumes of characters in Scratch. Depending on the progress of the participants, additional elements such as stage sets can be added.
Learning objectives:
Participants can control the movement of characters in Scratch. Participants understand the difference between characters and costumes. Participants can control the costumes of a character programmatically in Scratch.</description></item><item><title>Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/kuenstliche-intelligenz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/kuenstliche-intelligenz/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Artificial Intelligence&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants explore how AI works and what this technology can be used for. Using the Monkey Game as an example, participants discover how AI &amp;ldquo;learns.&amp;rdquo; Then, with the help of the website Machine Learning for Kids they can train and experiment with AI themselves. The model can also be used in Scratch at the end.
Learning objectives:
Participants know what AI is. Participants know how AI can be trained.</description></item><item><title>Astro Pi - Code in Space</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/python-astropi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/python-astropi/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Astro Pi - Code in Space&amp;rdquo; as part of the project &amp;ldquo;Mission Zero&amp;rdquo; of the RaspberryPi Foundation, participants will be given the opportunity to write a Python programme, to write a Python programme that will then be played on the ISS. Participants can create an animation lasting a maximum of 30 seconds, in which at least the humidity on the ISS is displayed. In addition, participants can greet the astronauts, display the air pressure and temperature or add pictures.</description></item><item><title>Between Ladybugs and Building Blocks</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/karol-und-kara/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/karol-und-kara/</guid><description>In the workshop &amp;ldquo;Between Ladybugs and Building Blocks,&amp;rdquo; participants, with the help of our ladybug Kara and our building block figure Robot Karol, get a first glimpse into the world of programming and algorithms. Kara and Robot Karol are programming environments designed for children and teenagers. First, all participants familiarize themselves with Kara and Karol and can discover functions and possibilities on their own. Then, tasks with various levels of difficulty can be solved or participants can implement their own ideas, such as guiding Karol through a self-built maze.</description></item><item><title>Club / Association</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/verein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/verein/</guid><description>The CoderDojo Schöneweide is a registered association. The non-profit status is pending. We are also a member Dojo of CoderDojo Deutschland e.V..
Membership Anyone can become a member. Simply send us an informal membership application via email. Resignation from membership is also informal and can be done via email.
Documents Satzung Annual reports 2023 2022</description></item><item><title>Creative Programming with Godot</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/godot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/godot/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Creative Programming with Godot&amp;rdquo; is aimed at teenagers or educators and mentors. Here, participants can, after an introduction to game design and an overview of the game engine &amp;ldquo;Godot,&amp;rdquo; design their own &amp;ldquo;platformer&amp;rdquo; game and begin implementation. Educators can explore the challenges and opportunities of game development.
Learning objectives:
Participants have a basic understanding of the game development process. Participants know how to work with Godot fundamentally. Participants can use basic scenes and node trees from Godot.</description></item><item><title>Dashbot Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/dashbot-challenges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/dashbot-challenges/</guid><description>In the Challenges workshop with Dash robots, participants will go through various task setups and learn to control and program a small robot in a playful manner.
As the tasks are very open-ended, participants can develop and try out their own solution ideas.
The DashBots A DashBot can be controlled via a connected iPad using the &amp;ldquo;Wonder&amp;rdquo; app. In the Wonder app, the DashBot can be manually controlled (Control), small programming tasks can be played (Robot Saga), and it can be freely programmed (Developer mode).</description></item><item><title>Datenschutzerklärung</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/datenschutz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/datenschutz/</guid><description>In dieser Datenschutzerklärung (Stand: 26.07.2023) erläutern wir basierend auf der Datenschutz-Grundverordnung (EU) 2016/679 und anwendbaren nationalen Gesetzen, welche personenbezogenen Daten (kurz Daten) wir als Verantwortliche – und die von uns beauftragten Auftragsverarbeiter:innen (z. B. Provider) – verarbeiten, zukünftig verarbeiten werden und welche rechtmäßigen Möglichkeiten Sie haben.
Rechtsgrundlagen Die Datenschutz-Grundverordnung (EU) 2016/679 und das deutsche Bundesdatenschutzgesetz (BDSG). legen den Rahmen fest, in dem wir personenbezogene Daten verarbeiten.
Wir verarbeiten Ihre Daten nur, wenn mindestens eine der folgenden Bedingungen zutrifft:</description></item><item><title>Dramas with llamas</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-theaterstueck/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-theaterstueck/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Dramas with llamas&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to make simple animations with Scratch. The focus of the workshop is on characters speaking and interacting with each other - just like in a theatre play. To ensure that what is said does not overlap, the interaction must be planned in terms of timing: who says what for how long, and so who waits how long? More advanced participants learn how to synchronise the interaction of the characters more efficiently, how to use Scratch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;send&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;receive&amp;rdquo; commands.</description></item><item><title>Hello Bot, how are you?</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/chatbot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/chatbot/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Hello Bot, how are you?&amp;rdquo; participants will gain insight into how to program chatbots. Chatbots are programs capable of conversing with a user. Participants can choose to use either Scratch or Python.
Depending on the participants&amp;rsquo; progress, when using Scratch, they can also utilize the &amp;ldquo;Text-to-Speech&amp;rdquo; extension and create their own blocks (also known as &amp;ldquo;functions&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;subroutines&amp;rdquo;).
Learning objectives:
Participants understand what a chatbot is. Participants can make the computer say something.</description></item><item><title>How to: Look after the child in the workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/parents/dosanddonts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/parents/dosanddonts/</guid><description>Sometimes you try to explain something to your child, but it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t click? With us, it&amp;rsquo;s all about having fun. That&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s important for you as a parent to support your child optimally.
Consider:
your child&amp;rsquo;s individual learning style, including factors like concentration and their own problem-solving methods. your child wants to pursue their own project, not yours! feel free to assist with problems through targeted questions. sometimes, just showing that parents make mistakes too is enough.</description></item><item><title>Improving the world as a software developer</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the world as a software developer&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an initial insight into working as a software developer. In the first part, the participants deal with topics that are close to their hearts, such as climate protection or equal rights, and think together about how software influences society. In the next step, the participants design a piece of software that draws attention to a social issue or that addresses a social problem.</description></item><item><title>Improving the World Through Games</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the World Through Games,&amp;rdquo; participants will get a first glimpse into the work of a game designer. In the first part, participants will discuss whether and how games can positively influence society. Then, participants will design their own game idea and have the opportunity to implement part of the idea using Scratch.
Learning objectives:
Participants will gain an impression of what a game designer does. Participants will be familiar with the fundamental elements of a game concept: story, graphics, sound, micro and macro goals, controls.</description></item><item><title>It speaks!</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-lippensynchronisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-lippensynchronisation/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;It speaks!&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants will gain an insight into how to make fluid animations consisting of individual images with Scratch. In this type of animation, several images are played one after the other, so that a kind of &amp;ldquo;film&amp;rdquo; is created in the mind - like a flip book, but digital! Lip synchronisation is a special type of frame-by-frame animation: a digital figure moves its mouth A digital figure moves the mouth so that the movements match the words spoken.</description></item><item><title>Legal Notice</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/impressum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/impressum/</guid><description>Information according to § 5 TMG. JavaScript must be enabled to display contact details.
Contact person: Linda Fernsel Address: Show Address
Email: Show Email
Phone number: Show Phone Number
Some icons on our site are based on the corresponding solid icons from Font Awesome and are licensed under CC-BY-4.0.</description></item><item><title>Making digital greeting cards</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Making digital greeting cards&amp;rdquo;, participants will gain an insight into how to make animations with Scratch and create beautiful digital greeting cards. The animations are created through the movement, costume changes and graphic effects of characters in Scratch. Depending on the progress of the participants, other means of animation can also be used, such as cloning figures or using the &amp;ldquo;colouring pen&amp;rdquo;.
Learning objectives:
Participants can play sounds in Scratch Participants can create simple graphics using the Scratch graphics editor.</description></item><item><title>mBot Obstacle Course</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/mbot-labyrinth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/mbot-labyrinth/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;mBot Obstacle Course,&amp;rdquo; participants navigate an mBot through an obstacle course. After a programming phase, two teams compete against each other: Who can be the first to burst the balloon in the middle of the course? Line and proximity sensors are used for traversing the course.
The mBlock programs for controlling the mBots are shared by the participants with on-site mentors, who then execute the programs. Since the mBots are captured by a camera mounted on the ceiling, participants can follow live to see if their program is working.</description></item><item><title>Pet App</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/octostudio-haustierapp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/octostudio-haustierapp/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Pet App&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants get an insight into how to program a digital pet that gets hungry and needs to be fed. OctoStudio is used for this purpose, which is an app for mobile devices that allows you to program apps. After a short round of inspiration, participants, together with their mentors, parents, or alone, use the guide provided by us to program a basic pet app and get to know OctoStudio.</description></item><item><title>Photo filter app</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/pocketcode-gesichtserkennung/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/pocketcode-gesichtserkennung/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Photo filter app&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to programme intelligent photo filters, so-called &amp;ldquo;lenses&amp;rdquo;, such as those found on Instagram or SnapChat. PocketCode, an app for mobile devices that can be used to programme apps, is used for this. After a short, creative warm-up exercise in which the participants design four filters on different topics in a short space of time, together with their mentor, parents or alone, the participants use the instructions we have put together to create their own photo filter.</description></item><item><title>Processing</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/processing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/processing/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Processing&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants learn about the Processing tool, which can be used to generate images and animations. can be generated. To do this, participants take their first steps in programming with Java and solve their first puzzles before inventing their own creative images.
Learning objectives:
Participants can operate the Processing environment Participants know basic processing commands Participants need:
Computer with Java 11, JRE11 and the Processing IDE installed</description></item><item><title>Shared Story</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/gemeinsame-geschichte/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/gemeinsame-geschichte/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Shared Story&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants first learn what programming is. With the game &amp;ldquo;Living Robot,&amp;rdquo; they get to know the basics of algorithmic thinking. Then, they can take their first steps in programming with Scratch and get to know the programming environment.
Separately from the workshop (e.g., in German and art classes), participants choose a story (e.g., a myth they have studied). This story is divided into small sections and distributed among participant groups.</description></item><item><title>Storyboarding and animations with Scratch</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-animationen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-animationen/</guid><description>In this workshop, participants design animations on topics that concern them in everyday life, such as friendship and the environment. Participants will gain an insight into elements of an animated film and how it is created: Brainstorming, storyboarding, animation and testing.
Learning objectives:
Participants can identify emotion-transporting elements of an animated film concept. Participants can create a storyboard for a scene. Participants can create simple graphics using the Scratch graphics editor.</description></item><item><title>What is the CoderDojo? - For parents</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/parents/infos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/parents/infos/</guid><description>What is the aim of CoderDojo Schöneweide? CoderDojo Schöneweide is an organisation that aims to teach children and young people about programming in a fun way. You can find a short teaser video here.
Can my child take part? Yes.
However, it would be helpful if they can already read. We also have an upper age limit of 17 years (17 years is ok, 18 is not). After that, you are welcome to join as a mentor :)</description></item></channel></rss>