<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spiel on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/spiel/</link><description>Recent content in Spiel on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/spiel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Minecraft Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-08-minecraft/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-08-minecraft/</guid><description>&lt;p>We, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary workshop at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus on January 8th, 2022.
&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/minecraft_image1.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The motto this time was &amp;ldquo;MINECRAFT&amp;rdquo;! Or rather Minecraft Redstone. Redstone is an object that serves as a manufacturing recipe. This makes it possible to build lines made of so-called redstone dust. These lines can then transmit redstone signals. This also enables the construction of larger redstone circuits. We showed our young participants how it is possible to build small circuits in Minecraft.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Between beetles and building blocks workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-24-zwischen-kaefern-und-blaukloetzen-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-24-zwischen-kaefern-und-blaukloetzen-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>We, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary workshop on 20.11.21 at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Under the motto “Between Beetles and Building Blocks”, our little ladybird Kara and our brick figure Robot Karol helped us to understand the world of programming and algorithms. Kara and Robot Karol are programming environments designed for children and young people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a brief introduction to Kara, the children were able to get to know and operate the program independently. For example, Kara the ladybird can move mushrooms or sit on clover leaves and place them in other places.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gruselige Party zum 10. Geburtstag von CoderDojo</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-01-grusel-geburtstagsparty-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-01-grusel-geburtstagsparty-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>Can you believe it? CoderDojo is already celebrating its tenth anniversary! And we, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, have turned 2
years old. These milestones need to be celebrated! Just in time for Halloween, we, the CoderDojo
Schöneweide, organized a voluntary spooky birthday party workshop at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus.
Wilhelminenhof campus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were delicious homemade cupcakes, balloons, costumes and, of course, young, determined programmers!
Everything a CoderDojo party needs to be a success.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FEZ Phenomena Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-25-fez-phaenomenien-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 22:24:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-25-fez-phaenomenien-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the fall vacations in Berlin and the FEZ Berlin invited children and their families to marvel, explore and play.
play. The fall vacations were not supposed to be boring. We from CoderDojo Schöneweide were also there with 2 voluntary
organized workshops on site. Our energetic mentors played and programmed together with the children
small, lively Dash robots that could be operated with a tablet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/fez-phaenomenien-workshop_img0.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were a total of 5 different challenges to overcome at both workshops. The children
were given a clipboard with a sheet of paper on which the 5 different challenges were illustrated.
were shown. There were 2 tasks for each challenge. The young participants received a colored sticker for each completed task
sticker for each completed task - one for taking part and one for programming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving the world through games</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-11-mit-spielen-die-welt-verbessern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-11-mit-spielen-die-welt-verbessern/</guid><description>&lt;p>We from CoderDojo Schöneweide also offered a volunteer workshop at the Treptow-Köpenick Volunteer Days as part of the Berlin Volunteer Days. On Saturday morning, 11.09.21, everything revolved around how we can improve the world with games. There are two questions we need to answer. Firstly, what does it actually mean to make the world a better place? Secondly, how can we do this with games? To approach these questions naturally, we first discussed our favorite games.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your own lens</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-20-deine-eigene-lense/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-20-deine-eigene-lense/</guid><description>&lt;p>On Friday, 20.08.2021, three mentors held a workshop on the topic of “Your own Lense”.
Four children and their parents took part in the workshop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/deine-eigene-lense_foto1.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea for our workshop was for the children to program their own photo filters with the “Pocket Code” app and have fun doing so.
At the beginning, we did a short round of introductions to warm up. Then we played a game in which we mentors set a topic for each round.
each round, and the children then designed a matching photo filter on paper in a short space of time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summer, sun, games! An experience report</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-juli-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-juli-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the middle of the summer vacations, the sun only peeked through the clouds from time to time on Thursday, but there was no end of fun programming games.&lt;br>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="images/Picknick.jpeg" width="90%">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;h4>Programmieren unter freiem Himmel - ein erster Eindruck&lt;/h4>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/juli-workshop_picknick.jpeg" alt="" title="Open-air programming - a first impression">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Under the open sky in a relaxed picnic atmosphere, all participants were finally able to talk to each other in person. It was a bit unusual for everyone to get to know each other first, but eventually everyone had their say (including the parents! :)) to talk about their vacation experiences.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>June Workshop 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-06-juni-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-06-juni-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 22.06.2021 we got together and organized a scratch workshop.
It was quite a small workshop this time, so close to the summer vacations, but the small group made the atmosphere very relaxed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As always at the beginning of a workshop, the mentors introduced themselves so that the participants knew who they could turn to if they had any questions.
This time, it was also possible for the participants to introduce themselves right at the beginning. This had the advantage that the participants were involved early on
and were thus on the same level as the mentors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scratch Week 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-20-scratch-week/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-20-scratch-week/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just in time for &lt;a href="https://sip.scratch.mit.edu/scratchweek/">Scratch Week&lt;/a>, we held a workshop on 20.05.2021 in which
where children could realize their own projects with the help of Scratch. 8 pupils of different ages took part
and 4 mentors who organized and led the workshop. The theme of the workshop was “Magical Arcade”.
A theme that the children could use as a guide and that gave them plenty of scope for ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/scratch-week_moinmoin.png" alt="" title="\“Moin Moin\” says the beetle">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Girls Day 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-04-22-girls-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-04-22-girls-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>At our Girls Day 2021 workshop, we primarily explored the interplay between software and society.
On April 22, 2021, 18 schoolgirls sat down together with 7 mentors (virtually, of course) and explored the question of how
explored the question of how software influences our social lives. Does it do that at all? Where does it do it?
And is it even good the way it does it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/girls-day_wiekommstduzurschule.png" alt="" title="A project idea: How do you get to school??">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>“Make your own games - Our first online workshop”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-09-08-workshop-game-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 13:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-09-08-workshop-game-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>Designing a game is quite complicated: You have to think about the story you want to tell,
what graphics or music you need, you have to design user-friendly menus and controls and of course
you also have to manage to motivate the users! Of course, you can&amp;rsquo;t learn all this in a single workshop,
but at least we were able to offer the participants of our online workshop on September 5, 2020 an introduction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>“Introduction to computer science for primary school pupils - you can learn a lot even without a computer!”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-04-03-workshop-einstieg-in-die-informatik/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 13:51:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-04-03-workshop-einstieg-in-die-informatik/</guid><description>&lt;p>How do I tell a robot how to make a sandwich, clear garbage in the park or catch a balloon?
On March 5, 2020, a sixth grade class from the Grundschule an der Wuhlheide was able to find out at our introductory programming workshop at HTW.
programming at the HTW. One of the most important findings from this workshop was certainly
Computer science education is possible with analog games even without expensive technical equipment!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>