<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Grundschule on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/grundschule/</link><description>Recent content in Grundschule on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/grundschule/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chatbot with Scratch 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-12-11-chatbot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-12-11-chatbot/</guid><description>Last week, we met again on the Wilhelminenhof campus of HTW Berlin and let the children program a chatbot with the help of Scratch. Once all the children had found their way to us, we got started after a short round of introductions and the question “What is your favorite robot (Bender Futurama!)”.
The children got to grips well with the week&amp;rsquo;s topic. The first attempts to design a chatbot were accomplished with the support of mentors.</description></item><item><title>Improving the world through games</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-11-mit-spielen-die-welt-verbessern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-11-mit-spielen-die-welt-verbessern/</guid><description>We from CoderDojo Schöneweide also offered a volunteer workshop at the Treptow-Köpenick Volunteer Days as part of the Berlin Volunteer Days. On Saturday morning, 11.09.21, everything revolved around how we can improve the world with games. There are two questions we need to answer. Firstly, what does it actually mean to make the world a better place? Secondly, how can we do this with games? To approach these questions naturally, we first discussed our favorite games.</description></item><item><title>Your own lens</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-20-deine-eigene-lense/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-20-deine-eigene-lense/</guid><description>On Friday, 20.08.2021, three mentors held a workshop on the topic of “Your own Lense”. Four children and their parents took part in the workshop.
The idea for our workshop was for the children to program their own photo filters with the “Pocket Code” app and have fun doing so. At the beginning, we did a short round of introductions to warm up. Then we played a game in which we mentors set a topic for each round.</description></item><item><title>Summer, sun, games! An experience report</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-juli-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-juli-workshop/</guid><description>In the middle of the summer vacations, the sun only peeked through the clouds from time to time on Thursday, but there was no end of fun programming games.
Programmieren unter freiem Himmel - ein erster Eindruck Under the open sky in a relaxed picnic atmosphere, all participants were finally able to talk to each other in person. It was a bit unusual for everyone to get to know each other first, but eventually everyone had their say (including the parents!</description></item><item><title>June Workshop 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-06-juni-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-06-juni-workshop/</guid><description>On 22.06.2021 we got together and organized a scratch workshop. It was quite a small workshop this time, so close to the summer vacations, but the small group made the atmosphere very relaxed.
As always at the beginning of a workshop, the mentors introduced themselves so that the participants knew who they could turn to if they had any questions. This time, it was also possible for the participants to introduce themselves right at the beginning.</description></item><item><title>Scratch Week 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-20-scratch-week/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-05-20-scratch-week/</guid><description>Just in time for Scratch Week, we held a workshop on 20.05.2021 in which where children could realize their own projects with the help of Scratch. 8 pupils of different ages took part and 4 mentors who organized and led the workshop. The theme of the workshop was “Magical Arcade”. A theme that the children could use as a guide and that gave them plenty of scope for ideas.
At the beginning of the workshop, the mentors introduced themselves so that the participants knew who to ask if anything was unclear.</description></item><item><title>Girls Day 2021</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-04-22-girls-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-04-22-girls-day/</guid><description>At our Girls Day 2021 workshop, we primarily explored the interplay between software and society. On April 22, 2021, 18 schoolgirls sat down together with 7 mentors (virtually, of course) and explored the question of how explored the question of how software influences our social lives. Does it do that at all? Where does it do it? And is it even good the way it does it?
The participants showed particular interest in the topics of environmental protection and sustainability.</description></item><item><title>“Make your own games - Our first online workshop”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-09-08-workshop-game-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 13:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-09-08-workshop-game-design/</guid><description>Designing a game is quite complicated: You have to think about the story you want to tell, what graphics or music you need, you have to design user-friendly menus and controls and of course you also have to manage to motivate the users! Of course, you can&amp;rsquo;t learn all this in a single workshop, but at least we were able to offer the participants of our online workshop on September 5, 2020 an introduction.</description></item><item><title>“Introduction to computer science for primary school pupils - you can learn a lot even without a computer!”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-04-03-workshop-einstieg-in-die-informatik/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 13:51:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-04-03-workshop-einstieg-in-die-informatik/</guid><description>How do I tell a robot how to make a sandwich, clear garbage in the park or catch a balloon? On March 5, 2020, a sixth grade class from the Grundschule an der Wuhlheide was able to find out at our introductory programming workshop at HTW. programming at the HTW. One of the most important findings from this workshop was certainly Computer science education is possible with analog games even without expensive technical equipment!</description></item></channel></rss>