<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Htw on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/htw/</link><description>Recent content in Htw on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/htw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Badges in CoderDojo</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-09-19-abzeichen-im-coderdojo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-09-19-abzeichen-im-coderdojo/</guid><description>Today you can find badges or trophy systems in many learning platforms or learning apps. They are designed to motivate learning enthusiasts such as children, for example, in order to promote fun and learning progress. I asked myself to what extent badges and trophy systems can encourage children to learn programming and how they influence a child&amp;rsquo;s fun and self-motivation.
To do this, I first looked at research on the use of badges in education.</description></item><item><title>Coding in March</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-19-coding-im-dojo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-19-coding-im-dojo/</guid><description>Despite the beautiful weather, we spent this Saturday morning indoors. This time we got straight into our projects without any introductions. New game elements were added to almost finished games. Games that had just been thought up were started again.
If you want to implement certain game mechanics, Scratch is the perfect foundation, just like designers who focus on character development or future authors who want to tell their story in a playful way.</description></item><item><title>Hack Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-12-htw-hackt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-03-12-htw-hackt/</guid><description>In movies, hackers often sit in dark rooms, shrouded in eternal night. Our workshop in cooperation with HTW Hackt showed that there is another way: it was a sunny Saturday afternoon, blue skies and bright rooms in which our ninjas could train. The topic this time was XSS, which stands for cross-site scripting and simply put means executing code on websites via input fields.
Since you can&amp;rsquo;t just hack in everywhere, the people from HTW Hackt created a website themselves, which the participants were allowed to explore.</description></item><item><title>Programming for Space - Astro Pi Workshop - Part Two</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-29-astropi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-29-astropi/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Brighten up the daily routine of the astronauts on the International Space Station.&amp;rdquo; - Cheer up the everyday life of astronauts on the International Space Station (ISS). That is the goal of the Mission Zero project, which we worked on together on January 29. A total of six children and young people took part. It was about the ISS. It was about temperature, humidity and pressure measurements using appropriate sensors. It was about Python programming on Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>CoderDojo Schöneweide - Corporate Design</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-31-corporate-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-31-corporate-design/</guid><description>I came across the “CoderDojo Schöneweide” project at HTW and wanted to take part in it. As my strengths lie more in the area of design and programming, I looked for an alternative job to mentoring within the Dojo. I was welcomed with open arms and found out with the help of the other members that the team was still looking for someone to take care of the corporate design and revise the current design.</description></item><item><title>Minecraft Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-08-minecraft/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-08-minecraft/</guid><description>We, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary workshop at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus on January 8th, 2022. The motto this time was &amp;ldquo;MINECRAFT&amp;rdquo;! Or rather Minecraft Redstone. Redstone is an object that serves as a manufacturing recipe. This makes it possible to build lines made of so-called redstone dust. These lines can then transmit redstone signals. This also enables the construction of larger redstone circuits. We showed our young participants how it is possible to build small circuits in Minecraft.</description></item><item><title>Between beetles and building blocks workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-24-zwischen-kaefern-und-blaukloetzen-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-24-zwischen-kaefern-und-blaukloetzen-workshop/</guid><description>We, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary workshop on 20.11.21 at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus.
Under the motto “Between Beetles and Building Blocks”, our little ladybird Kara and our brick figure Robot Karol helped us to understand the world of programming and algorithms. Kara and Robot Karol are programming environments designed for children and young people.
After a brief introduction to Kara, the children were able to get to know and operate the program independently.</description></item><item><title>Gruselige Party zum 10. Geburtstag von CoderDojo</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-01-grusel-geburtstagsparty-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-01-grusel-geburtstagsparty-workshop/</guid><description>Can you believe it? CoderDojo is already celebrating its tenth anniversary! And we, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, have turned 2 years old. These milestones need to be celebrated! Just in time for Halloween, we, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary spooky birthday party workshop at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus. Wilhelminenhof campus.
There were delicious homemade cupcakes, balloons, costumes and, of course, young, determined programmers! Everything a CoderDojo party needs to be a success.</description></item></channel></rss>