<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scratch on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/scratch/</link><description>Recent content in Scratch on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/scratch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Animating a music video</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-musikvideo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-musikvideo/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Animating a music video&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to make simple animations with Scratch. The animations are created by moving and changing the costumes of characters in Scratch. Depending on the progress of the participants, additional elements such as stage sets can be added.
Learning objectives:
Participants can control the movement of characters in Scratch. Participants understand the difference between characters and costumes. Participants can control the costumes of a character programmatically in Scratch.</description></item><item><title>Dramas with llamas</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-theaterstueck/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-theaterstueck/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Dramas with llamas&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to make simple animations with Scratch. The focus of the workshop is on characters speaking and interacting with each other - just like in a theatre play. To ensure that what is said does not overlap, the interaction must be planned in terms of timing: who says what for how long, and so who waits how long? More advanced participants learn how to synchronise the interaction of the characters more efficiently, how to use Scratch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;send&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;receive&amp;rdquo; commands.</description></item><item><title>Hello Bot, how are you?</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/chatbot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/chatbot/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Hello Bot, how are you?&amp;rdquo; participants will gain insight into how to program chatbots. Chatbots are programs capable of conversing with a user. Participants can choose to use either Scratch or Python.
Depending on the participants&amp;rsquo; progress, when using Scratch, they can also utilize the &amp;ldquo;Text-to-Speech&amp;rdquo; extension and create their own blocks (also known as &amp;ldquo;functions&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;subroutines&amp;rdquo;).
Learning objectives:
Participants understand what a chatbot is. Participants can make the computer say something.</description></item><item><title>Improving the world as a software developer</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the world as a software developer&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an initial insight into working as a software developer. In the first part, the participants deal with topics that are close to their hearts, such as climate protection or equal rights, and think together about how software influences society. In the next step, the participants design a piece of software that draws attention to a social issue or that addresses a social problem.</description></item><item><title>Improving the World Through Games</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the World Through Games,&amp;rdquo; participants will get a first glimpse into the work of a game designer. In the first part, participants will discuss whether and how games can positively influence society. Then, participants will design their own game idea and have the opportunity to implement part of the idea using Scratch.
Learning objectives:
Participants will gain an impression of what a game designer does. Participants will be familiar with the fundamental elements of a game concept: story, graphics, sound, micro and macro goals, controls.</description></item><item><title>It speaks!</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-lippensynchronisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-lippensynchronisation/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;It speaks!&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants will gain an insight into how to make fluid animations consisting of individual images with Scratch. In this type of animation, several images are played one after the other, so that a kind of &amp;ldquo;film&amp;rdquo; is created in the mind - like a flip book, but digital! Lip synchronisation is a special type of frame-by-frame animation: a digital figure moves its mouth A digital figure moves the mouth so that the movements match the words spoken.</description></item><item><title>Making digital greeting cards</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Making digital greeting cards&amp;rdquo;, participants will gain an insight into how to make animations with Scratch and create beautiful digital greeting cards. The animations are created through the movement, costume changes and graphic effects of characters in Scratch. Depending on the progress of the participants, other means of animation can also be used, such as cloning figures or using the &amp;ldquo;colouring pen&amp;rdquo;.
Learning objectives:
Participants can play sounds in Scratch Participants can create simple graphics using the Scratch graphics editor.</description></item><item><title>Shared Story</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/gemeinsame-geschichte/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/gemeinsame-geschichte/</guid><description>In the &amp;ldquo;Shared Story&amp;rdquo; workshop, participants first learn what programming is. With the game &amp;ldquo;Living Robot,&amp;rdquo; they get to know the basics of algorithmic thinking. Then, they can take their first steps in programming with Scratch and get to know the programming environment.
Separately from the workshop (e.g., in German and art classes), participants choose a story (e.g., a myth they have studied). This story is divided into small sections and distributed among participant groups.</description></item><item><title>Storyboarding and animations with Scratch</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-animationen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-animationen/</guid><description>In this workshop, participants design animations on topics that concern them in everyday life, such as friendship and the environment. Participants will gain an insight into elements of an animated film and how it is created: Brainstorming, storyboarding, animation and testing.
Learning objectives:
Participants can identify emotion-transporting elements of an animated film concept. Participants can create a storyboard for a scene. Participants can create simple graphics using the Scratch graphics editor.</description></item></channel></rss>