<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fez on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/fez/</link><description>Recent content in Fez on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 17:10:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/fez/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FEZ - The Pixel Worlds February 23</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-02-18-die-pixelwelten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 17:10:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2023-02-18-die-pixelwelten/</guid><description>On two weekends, February 11 and 12 and February 18 and 19, kids were able to make their own VR goggles, design PixelArt or play Jump&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;Run SuperMario live in the gym at the FEZ leisure and recreation center.
We took part in the CoderDojo on the 11th and 12th with two workshops each entitled “Robot competitions”. We didn&amp;rsquo;t really have anything to do with competitions. Instead, similar to the crazy lab in November, there were a wide variety of challenges that had to be mastered with DashBots.</description></item><item><title>FEZ Crazy Lab Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-09-fez-verruecktes-labor-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 17:27:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-09-fez-verruecktes-labor-workshop/</guid><description>Last weekend, our Dashbot workshop took place for the second time at the FEZ, a popular event for kids and parents alike. Dashbot? - They&amp;rsquo;re those cute little blue robots that you can do all sorts of crazy things with. As part of the crazy lab at the FEZ, interested children were able to let off steam. The highlight is that the robots can be programmed in a beginner-friendly way. This means that all actions can also be carried out automatically.</description></item><item><title>FEZ Phenomena Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-25-fez-phaenomenien-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 22:24:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-25-fez-phaenomenien-workshop/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the fall vacations in Berlin and the FEZ Berlin invited children and their families to marvel, explore and play. play. The fall vacations were not supposed to be boring. We from CoderDojo Schöneweide were also there with 2 voluntary organized workshops on site. Our energetic mentors played and programmed together with the children small, lively Dash robots that could be operated with a tablet.
There were a total of 5 different challenges to overcome at both workshops.</description></item></channel></rss>