<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Freizeit on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/freizeit/</link><description>Recent content in Freizeit on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/freizeit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our first presence dojo during the Corona pandemic - A how-to</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-erster-live-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-erster-live-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>Two weeks before our July workshop, the idea came up that it might be possible to hold it live and outdoors. Enthusiastic about the idea, we first had to find out which framework conditions applied. In the end, the organizational effort was surprisingly easy to manage in 2 weeks:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The location&lt;/em>&lt;br>
In the shadow of the rising numbers at the end of July, “outside but still with access to electricity” was a relevant key point. By chance and spontaneously, we came across Sebastian from Remili, or Einhorn gGmbH, who was very accommodating. Thank you very much for that! Hopefully future workshops can also take place at Hasselwerderstr. 22A by arrangement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summer, sun, games! An experience report</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-juli-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-07-29-juli-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the middle of the summer vacations, the sun only peeked through the clouds from time to time on Thursday, but there was no end of fun programming games.&lt;br>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="images/Picknick.jpeg" width="90%">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;h4>Programmieren unter freiem Himmel - ein erster Eindruck&lt;/h4>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/juli-workshop_picknick.jpeg" alt="" title="Open-air programming - a first impression">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Under the open sky in a relaxed picnic atmosphere, all participants were finally able to talk to each other in person. It was a bit unusual for everyone to get to know each other first, but eventually everyone had their say (including the parents! :)) to talk about their vacation experiences.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>