<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pocketcode on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/pocketcode/</link><description>Recent content in Pocketcode on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 15:10:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/pocketcode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>“Photo filters with PocketCode - A workshop with kein Abseits e.V.”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-03-16-workshop-pocketcode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-03-16-workshop-pocketcode/</guid><description>You can use fun filters and “lenses” on SnapChat and Instagram, that add additional elements to your photo - for example, a pair of whiskers in just the right place. In our first PocketCode workshop, we designed and programmed our own smart photo filters.
We ran the workshop together with mentors from kein Abseits e.V., so that they can pass on their knowledge to their mentees. Only a few mentees at kein Abseits e.</description></item><item><title>Photo filter app</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/pocketcode-gesichtserkennung/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/pocketcode-gesichtserkennung/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Photo filter app&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an insight into how to programme intelligent photo filters, so-called &amp;ldquo;lenses&amp;rdquo;, such as those found on Instagram or SnapChat. PocketCode, an app for mobile devices that can be used to programme apps, is used for this. After a short, creative warm-up exercise in which the participants design four filters on different topics in a short space of time, together with their mentor, parents or alone, the participants use the instructions we have put together to create their own photo filter.</description></item></channel></rss>