<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Herbstferien on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/herbstferien/</link><description>Recent content in Herbstferien on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 17:27:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/herbstferien/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FEZ Crazy Lab Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-09-fez-verruecktes-labor-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 17:27:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-09-fez-verruecktes-labor-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last weekend, our Dashbot workshop took place for the second time at the FEZ, a popular event for kids and parents alike. Dashbot? - They&amp;rsquo;re those cute little blue robots that you can do all sorts of crazy things with. As part of the crazy lab at the FEZ, interested children were able to let off steam. The highlight is that the robots can be programmed in a beginner-friendly way. This means that all actions can also be carried out automatically. We were on site with mentors to answer any questions. This encouraged the children&amp;rsquo;s experimental curiosity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FEZ Phenomena Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-25-fez-phaenomenien-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 22:24:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-25-fez-phaenomenien-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the fall vacations in Berlin and the FEZ Berlin invited children and their families to marvel, explore and play.
play. The fall vacations were not supposed to be boring. We from CoderDojo Schöneweide were also there with 2 voluntary
organized workshops on site. Our energetic mentors played and programmed together with the children
small, lively Dash robots that could be operated with a tablet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/images/cms/fez-phaenomenien-workshop_img0.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were a total of 5 different challenges to overcome at both workshops. The children
were given a clipboard with a sheet of paper on which the 5 different challenges were illustrated.
were shown. There were 2 tasks for each challenge. The young participants received a colored sticker for each completed task
sticker for each completed task - one for taking part and one for programming.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>