<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Karol on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/karol/</link><description>Recent content in Karol on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/karol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Between beetles and building blocks workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-24-zwischen-kaefern-und-blaukloetzen-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-24-zwischen-kaefern-und-blaukloetzen-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;p>We, the CoderDojo Schöneweide, organized a voluntary workshop on 20.11.21 at the HTW Berlin on the Wilhelminenhof campus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Under the motto “Between Beetles and Building Blocks”, our little ladybird Kara and our brick figure Robot Karol helped us to understand the world of programming and algorithms. Kara and Robot Karol are programming environments designed for children and young people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a brief introduction to Kara, the children were able to get to know and operate the program independently. For example, Kara the ladybird can move mushrooms or sit on clover leaves and place them in other places.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Between Ladybugs and Building Blocks</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/karol-und-kara/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/karol-und-kara/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the workshop &amp;ldquo;Between Ladybugs and Building Blocks,&amp;rdquo; participants, with the help of our ladybug Kara and our building block figure Robot Karol, get a first glimpse into the world of programming and algorithms. Kara and Robot Karol are programming environments designed for children and teenagers. First, all participants familiarize themselves with Kara and Karol and can discover functions and possibilities on their own. Then, tasks with various levels of difficulty can be solved or participants can implement their own ideas, such as guiding Karol through a self-built maze.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>