<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 16:27:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Figma Prototyping Workshop: Adventskalender-App</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-12-17-figma-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 16:27:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-12-17-figma-workshop/</guid><description>Kurz vor Weihnachten fand ein Figma Prototyping Workshop für Kinder im Alter von 6 bis 12 Jahren statt. Bei diesem Workshop ging es darum, einen individuellen Adventskalender mit der Design-Software Figma zu erstellen. Die Teilnehmenden wurden mit einem vorgegebenen Adventskalender-Template ausgestattet, das sie nach ihren eigenen kreativen Vorstellungen gestalten sollten.
Adventskalender-Template in Figma
Die 5 Teilnehmenden haben sich bei der Gestaltung des Adventskalenders viele verschiedene Möglichkeiten ausgedacht. Einige haben hinter den Türchen Bilder hochgeladen, andere haben eigene kleine Designs erstellt.</description></item><item><title>CoderDojo Schöneweide - Corporate Design</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-31-corporate-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-31-corporate-design/</guid><description>I came across the “CoderDojo Schöneweide” project at HTW and wanted to take part in it. As my strengths lie more in the area of design and programming, I looked for an alternative job to mentoring within the Dojo. I was welcomed with open arms and found out with the help of the other members that the team was still looking for someone to take care of the corporate design and revise the current design.</description></item><item><title>“Photo filters with PocketCode - A workshop with kein Abseits e.V.”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-03-16-workshop-pocketcode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2021-03-16-workshop-pocketcode/</guid><description>You can use fun filters and “lenses” on SnapChat and Instagram, that add additional elements to your photo - for example, a pair of whiskers in just the right place. In our first PocketCode workshop, we designed and programmed our own smart photo filters.
We ran the workshop together with mentors from kein Abseits e.V., so that they can pass on their knowledge to their mentees. Only a few mentees at kein Abseits e.</description></item><item><title>“Make your own games - Our first online workshop”</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-09-08-workshop-game-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 13:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2020-09-08-workshop-game-design/</guid><description>Designing a game is quite complicated: You have to think about the story you want to tell, what graphics or music you need, you have to design user-friendly menus and controls and of course you also have to manage to motivate the users! Of course, you can&amp;rsquo;t learn all this in a single workshop, but at least we were able to offer the participants of our online workshop on September 5, 2020 an introduction.</description></item><item><title>Creative Programming with Godot</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/godot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/godot/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Creative Programming with Godot&amp;rdquo; is aimed at teenagers or educators and mentors. Here, participants can, after an introduction to game design and an overview of the game engine &amp;ldquo;Godot,&amp;rdquo; design their own &amp;ldquo;platformer&amp;rdquo; game and begin implementation. Educators can explore the challenges and opportunities of game development.
Learning objectives:
Participants have a basic understanding of the game development process. Participants know how to work with Godot fundamentally. Participants can use basic scenes and node trees from Godot.</description></item><item><title>Improving the world as a software developer</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the world as a software developer&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an initial insight into working as a software developer. In the first part, the participants deal with topics that are close to their hearts, such as climate protection or equal rights, and think together about how software influences society. In the next step, the participants design a piece of software that draws attention to a social issue or that addresses a social problem.</description></item><item><title>Improving the World Through Games</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the World Through Games,&amp;rdquo; participants will get a first glimpse into the work of a game designer. In the first part, participants will discuss whether and how games can positively influence society. Then, participants will design their own game idea and have the opportunity to implement part of the idea using Scratch.
Learning objectives:
Participants will gain an impression of what a game designer does. Participants will be familiar with the fundamental elements of a game concept: story, graphics, sound, micro and macro goals, controls.</description></item><item><title>Making digital greeting cards</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Making digital greeting cards&amp;rdquo;, participants will gain an insight into how to make animations with Scratch and create beautiful digital greeting cards. The animations are created through the movement, costume changes and graphic effects of characters in Scratch. Depending on the progress of the participants, other means of animation can also be used, such as cloning figures or using the &amp;ldquo;colouring pen&amp;rdquo;.
Learning objectives:
Participants can play sounds in Scratch Participants can create simple graphics using the Scratch graphics editor.</description></item></channel></rss>