<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creative Programming with Godot</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/godot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/godot/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Creative Programming with Godot&amp;rdquo; is aimed at teenagers or educators and mentors. Here, participants can, after an introduction to game design and an overview of the game engine &amp;ldquo;Godot,&amp;rdquo; design their own &amp;ldquo;platformer&amp;rdquo; game and begin implementation. Educators can explore the challenges and opportunities of game development.
Learning objectives:
Participants have a basic understanding of the game development process. Participants know how to work with Godot fundamentally. Participants can use basic scenes and node trees from Godot.</description></item><item><title>Improving the world as a software developer</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/softwareentwicklung-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the world as a software developer&amp;rdquo;, participants gain an initial insight into working as a software developer. In the first part, the participants deal with topics that are close to their hearts, such as climate protection or equal rights, and think together about how software influences society. In the next step, the participants design a piece of software that draws attention to a social issue or that addresses a social problem.</description></item><item><title>Improving the World Through Games</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/computerspiele-und-gesellschaft/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Improving the World Through Games,&amp;rdquo; participants will get a first glimpse into the work of a game designer. In the first part, participants will discuss whether and how games can positively influence society. Then, participants will design their own game idea and have the opportunity to implement part of the idea using Scratch.
Learning objectives:
Participants will gain an impression of what a game designer does. Participants will be familiar with the fundamental elements of a game concept: story, graphics, sound, micro and macro goals, controls.</description></item><item><title>Making digital greeting cards</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/scratch-grusskarten/</guid><description>In the online workshop &amp;ldquo;Making digital greeting cards&amp;rdquo;, participants will gain an insight into how to make animations with Scratch and create beautiful digital greeting cards. The animations are created through the movement, costume changes and graphic effects of characters in Scratch. Depending on the progress of the participants, other means of animation can also be used, such as cloning figures or using the &amp;ldquo;colouring pen&amp;rdquo;.
Learning objectives:
Participants can play sounds in Scratch Participants can create simple graphics using the Scratch graphics editor.</description></item></channel></rss>