<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dashbot on CoderDojo Schöneweide</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/dashbot/</link><description>Recent content in Dashbot on CoderDojo Schöneweide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 17:27:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/tags/dashbot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FEZ Crazy Lab Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-09-fez-verruecktes-labor-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 17:27:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/blog/2022-11-09-fez-verruecktes-labor-workshop/</guid><description>Last weekend, our Dashbot workshop took place for the second time at the FEZ, a popular event for kids and parents alike. Dashbot? - They&amp;rsquo;re those cute little blue robots that you can do all sorts of crazy things with. As part of the crazy lab at the FEZ, interested children were able to let off steam. The highlight is that the robots can be programmed in a beginner-friendly way. This means that all actions can also be carried out automatically.</description></item><item><title>Dashbot Workshop</title><link>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/dashbot-challenges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coderdojo-schoeneweide.github.io/en/workshops/dashbot-challenges/</guid><description>In the Challenges workshop with Dash robots, participants will go through various task setups and learn to control and program a small robot in a playful manner.
As the tasks are very open-ended, participants can develop and try out their own solution ideas.
The DashBots A DashBot can be controlled via a connected iPad using the &amp;ldquo;Wonder&amp;rdquo; app. In the Wonder app, the DashBot can be manually controlled (Control), small programming tasks can be played (Robot Saga), and it can be freely programmed (Developer mode).</description></item></channel></rss>